Info.md 9/2/2021

Task Z3

Name: Chow Jia Ying

Matriculation number: A0187457M

Cover Letter.md 9/2/2021

Dear Hiring Manager,

I am Jia Ying, an undergraduate from the National University of Singapore, majoring in Computer Science. I am writing to express my interest in the Software Engineer position in SoC QuickTalk.

With a few internship stints in frontend web development, I have experience contributing to production software in fast-moving industries such as cryptocurrencies and e-commerce. During my previous role as a Software Engineering Intern in Shopee, I worked on internal services used by operations teams in Shopee and was exposed to the software development lifecycle in there.

Besides my internships, I am someone who does my best to improve the team culture of any software development team I am a part of. I do my best to contribute ideas and take ownership of the product I am building.

Thank you for your time and consideration. I look forward to speaking with you about this opportunity.

Best Regards,

Chow Jia Ying

🛘 (+65) 9106 5108 | 🗷 chowjiaying@u.nus.edu | 🌴 c-likethis123.github.io/website | 🖸 C-likethis123 | 🛅 chow-jia-ying | 🜬 chowjiaying211

Education

National University of Singapore

Aug 2018 - May 2022

BACHELOR OF COMPUTING IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

- Focus Areas: Software Engineering, Programming Languages
- · Relevant coursework: Programming Methodology, Software Engineering, Programming Language Implementation
- · Participated in NUS Overseas College (Singapore), a 6 months program where students intern in startups and take entrepreneurship courses

Experience

Shopee Singapore May 2021 - Aug 2021

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN

- Implemented features for an internal portal that allows non-technical teams to deploy marketing assets to the Shopee app
- Developed a tool to allow non-technical teams to test and validate targeted marketing rulesets in Shopee's backend system
- Collaborated with backend teams to iterate on API specifications prior to feature implementation
- Technologies: React, Typescript, SCSS, Webpack, ESLint, Ant Design

Toppan Ecquaria Pte. Ltd. Feb 2021 - May 2021

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Explored integration of AWS Textract, Lambda and S3 to automate PDF text extraction for a PDF document search engine
- Implemented backend APIs in a Flask server to perform text extraction with Apache Tika and upload processed text to AWS ElasticSearch
- · Created frontend pages for document uploading, searching and management and integrated the relevant APIs
- Technologies: Flask, Javascript, HTML, AWS ElasticSearch, Apache Tika

Switcheo Jul 2020 - Dec 2020

FRONTEND DEVELOPER INTERN

- · Worked on the trading interface of DEMEX, a decentralised exchange for cryptocurrency margin and derivatives trading
- · Refactored the visual theming system of DEMEX to be more aligned with Material Ul's design patterns
- · Participated in usability tests and identified bugs, ensuring that bugs were caught and fixed in a timely manner
- · Reduced developers' time spent on manual formatting by configuring automatic linters for the codebases using TSLint
- Technologies: React, Redux, TypeScript, Material UI

Skills_

Programming Languages JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, Java, HTML5, CSS, Ruby, SQL, C

Frameworks NodeJS, React, Redux, Express, Ruby on Rails, Flask

Others Git, Heroku, Webpack, ESLint, Vite

Software Projects

Type Inference for Source 1 (https://github.com/C-likethis123/js-slang)

- Led a team of 3 to write a type inferencer for Source (a dialect of Javascript) programs in Typescript, that can infer types of constants, functions and conditionals
- Wrote automated test cases using the Jest framework to save time used to test code
- Technologies: Typescript, Jest

To Do List App (https://github.com/C-likethis123/cvwo-assignment-2019/)

- · Developed a full stack todo list web app where users can add recurring and one-off tasks
- Technologies: React, Ruby on Rails, Vite

Blogger Alternative (in progress) (https://github.com/C-likethis123/Blogger-Alternative/)

- · Developed a blog web app with Markdown support, where users can write blog posts for Google Blogger
- Technologies: MongoDB, Express, React, NodeJS, Reactstrap

TUI Font Size Picker (https://github.com/C-likethis123/tui-font-size-picker)

- Published a npm package that adds a font size picker in an online Markdown editor, receiving 103 downloads within its first week of publication
- Technologies: Webpack, Javascript, ESLint